BHARATHKUMARRAJU DASARAJU

SENIOR DEVOPS ENGINEER - HOOQ TV. SINGAPORE

ONLINE

http://bharathkumaraju.comin.linkedin.com/in/dasararaju

github.com/bharathkumarraiu

CONTACT BIO DETAILS

Singapore DOB: 12-June-1987 **t:** +65 90829964 Passport: J7879295

e: bhrth.dsra1@gmail.com





SUMMARY:

Over 8 years IT experience in DevOps and CLOUD in mission critical environments across the Streaming, Aviation, Financial and GPS industries.

Extensive hands-on of DevOps with strong analytical, design and problem solving skills.

Built a fully automated elastic stack based solution for log aggregation and data analytics running on docker containers.

Proven track of highly successful projects development in design, implementation, **automation**, **continuous deployment(CICD)** pipelines for real-time and low-latency applications.

TECHNICAL PROFILE:

DevOps AWS Cloud, Ansible, Terraform, Git, Bamboo, Vagrant, Docker, Github, Jira, Jenkins, Gradle, Nginx.

Elastic stack Elasticsearch, Kibana, Functionbeat, Logstash, Filebeat, metricbeat, packetbeat.

Monitoring/Log Sysdig,Newrelic,Datadog,AppDynamics,Sumologic,sensu,flapjack,Grafana,graphite.

Programming Python, Shell Scripting, Java. RDBMS Oracle, PostgreSQL, MySQL.

OS Linux: RedHat, CentOS. Debian, Ubuntu, Coreos, Redhat Atomic

Infrastructure Docker, Kubernetes, Virtual Machine, Vagrant, Amazon Web Service, Google Cloud Platform.

Certifications AWS Solution Architect and VMware Cloud Professional

EXPERIENCE:

HOOQ TV, Dockerized the applications and moved them from EC2 to ECS Cluster.

Singapore, Implemented IAC(Infrastructure As a Code) using terraform for AWS cloud were dockerized apps are running.

(2019-2020) Implemented CICD Pipeline using github actions for the entire HOOQ.

Singapore Airlines,

Singapore (2019) Automated AWS Cloud deployments and builds using the Jenkinsfile. Implemented automated Stack deployments using Cloud Formation. Working on openshift container platform to move legacy apps to k8s.

Delivion GmBH,Automated Bamboo deployments and builds using the Bamboo specs. **Essen,Germany**Implemented automated backup solution for complex applications.

(2018-2019) Worked in k8s setup and federated Prometheus monitoring for the k8s cluster and apps.

Standard Chartered,

Chennai, India (2016-2018) Automated Complicated WebMethods Stack Provisioning using CICD pipeline. Implemented Centralized log aggregation/Analytics using Elastic

Stack.

Implemented k8s Multi-master setup for containerized solution.

Trimble Navigation,

Worked on Immutable automated deployments using Cliqr/Terraform.

Chennai, India (2014-2016) $Created\ Development,\ QA,\ Stage,\ Production\ stacks\ \&\ maintained\ them\ securely\ using\ robust\ VPC\ design.$

Automated resource cleanup using AWS Lambda as part of cost saving effort.

 $Implemented\ application\ monitoring\ using\ DataDog\ \&\ integrated\ with\ AWS\ environment.$

Hewlett-Packard, Chennai, India (2011-2014) Administered DHCP,DNS, LDAP, AD and NFS services on RHEL in Development/Production environments. Automating the deployment of Middleware Applications to RHEL DEV/PROD servers on VMWare ESX.

EDUCATION:

MCA-Post Graduation Information System and Computer Science

(Jun2007-Jun2010) UNIX Networking, Java, Information Systems, information security, e-business

BSC- Graduation Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry

(Jul2004-May2007) Courses: Applied Mathematics, Organic Chemistry, Atomic Physics.

LANGUAGES:

Fluent in English, Telugu, Tamil, Hindi, German.

INTERESTS:

Technology trends and news, travelling, football, movies.